juniqe.com 2019-04-07

# Privacy Policy | JUNIQE

### Data protection

Notes on data protection   
Protecting your privacy is very important to us. Our privacy policy provides information on how we use and protect your data on the JUNIQE website. 

**Website operator**   
The JUNIQE website is operated by:   
Kollwitz Internet GmbH   
Köpenicker Straße 126,   
10179 Berlin, Germany (hereinafter "JUNIQE")   
Contact: [service@juniqe.com](mailto:service@juniqe.com)  
You can reach our data protection officer at [data-privacy@juniqe.com](mailto:data-privacy@juniqe.com)  

**  
Data collection and storage  
**  
You can visit our website without telling us who you are or providing any personal data. We will only save the following access data without any personally identifying information, even if you are coming to our website from a newsletter link:

\- The name of your internet service provider (ISP)   
\- The website you are coming to us from   
\- The name of the requested file 

This data is used solely for the purpose of improving our services and cannot be traced back to you. We collect, store, and process your data in order to complete your purchase order and handle any subsequent guarantee claims, as well as for promotional purposes. 

We collect and process the following personal data about you when you visit our website, or if you voluntarily provide us with it when ordering, creating a customer account, or registering for our newsletter: 

\- Your contact information including your email address   
\- Your account details from the ordering process   
\- Online identifiers 

What are online identifiers? When you visit a website, your browser sends information about your browser type and version, your operating system, your referrer URL, your IP address, the file name, your access status, the amount of transferred data, the date and time of the server request. This information is pseudonymised and doesn’t personally identify you.

**Purpose**  
We process your data for the following purposes:   
\- Contacting you   
\- Promotional purposes   
\- Quality assurance   
\- Our statistics   
\- Processing your sales contract   
\- Sending our newsletter

**  
Legal basis**  
We process your data in accordance with the following legal basis:   
\- With your consent (article 6, paragraph 1, lit. a) GDPR)   
\- To execute a sales contract with you (article 6, paragraph 1 lit. b) GDPR)   
\- When a legitimate interest on our part applies (article 6, paragraph 1, lit. f) GDPR), namely for the improvement of our service, the protection against misuse, and for our statistics

**Third parties**  
If you made a purchase we forward your personal data to contracted service providers that we use to complete your order (e.g. manufacturers, shipping partners or payment service providers). If you have signed up for the newsletter, the personal data that you provided upon registration will be used to send you personalised newsletters. No data will be shared with third parties. Our privacy policies are in accordance with the Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG) and the Telemedia Act (TMG) of the Federal Republic of Germany.

**Data sources**   
The data we receive comes from you (including data about the devices you are using).

**Duration of storage**   
We will store your data:   
\- If you have consented to the processing of your data, until you withdraw this consent, otherwise after 6 months, or, depending on the specific type of data, in accordance with the relevant storage period prescribed by law.   
\- If we need the data to implement a contract, at most for as long as the contractual relationship with you is in effect, or for as long as legal retention periods are applicable.   
\- If we use your data on the basis of our legitimate interests, at most so long as it does not outweigh your interest to have this data deleted or anonymised.

**Legitimate interests**   
When processing your data, we pursue the following legitimate interests:   
\- The improvement of our service   
\- The protection against misuse   
\- Statistics

**Recipients or categories of recipients of personalised data**   
When processing your data, we work with the following service providers who have access to your data:   
\- Shipping partners   
\- Web hosting providers   
\- Providers of social media platforms   
\- Advertising networks (for ads)   
\- Providers of web analysis tools

**Your rights as an affected party**   
According to article 15 ff. of the GDPR, you have—partly subject to certain conditions—the right to:   
\- Request information on the processing of your data   
\- Amend your data   
\- Delete or disable your data  
\- Limit your data   
\- Object to the processing of your data   
\- Receive your data in a transferable format and forward this to a third party   
\- Withdraw your consent to the processing of your data for the future   
\- File a complaint with the responsible oversight authority about prohibited use of your data. The relevant authority is the Berliner Beauftragte für Datenschutz und Informationsfreiheit, Friedrichstr. 219, 10969 Berlin, Germany.

**Requirement or obligation relating to the provision of data**   
Unless otherwise specified when collecting the data, the provision of data is neither necessary nor compulsory.

### **Further information on data protection**

**Contact**   
The easiest way to get in touch with us quickly is by contacting us via email at: [service@juniqe.com](mailto:service@juniqe.com)

**Email newsletter**   
By subscribing to our free newsletter you will be the first to learn about new products, valuable tips and news, as well as exclusive offers. After signing up you will receive a confirmation email with an activation link to begin receiving the newsletter. If you no longer wish to receive our newsletter you can unsubscribe at any time, simply by clicking the “unsubscribe" link in the footer of any of our newsletters or by sending an email to unsubscribe@juniqe.com.

 **Product recommendations via email**  
According to Section 7 para. 3 Act Against Unfair Competition (UWG) of the Federal Republic of Germany we are entitled to use the email address specified during a purchase in our shop for direct marketing activities for our own similar products or services. If you do not wish to receive our product recommendations any longer, you can unsubscribe from them at any time without costs other than the transmission costs pursuant to the basic tariffs being incurred in this regard. Unsubscription can simply be done by clicking the “unsubscribe" link in the footer of any of our product recommendations or by sending an email to [unsubscribe@juniqe.com](mailto:unsubscribe@juniqe.com).

**Data security**   
For every customer who registers accordingly, we set up a password-protected direct access to the inventory data we store on them via a customer account. Here, you can view data relating to your completed, open, and recently sent orders, in addition to managing your address data and newsletter settings. The transfer of this data to the following places is encrypted: 

* Login / * Customer account / * Shopping cart / * Ordering process 

We secure our website and other systems through technical and organisational measures against loss, destruction, access, change, and distribution of your data by unauthorised persons. You should always treat your login details confidentially and close your browser window when you have finished visiting our website, particularly if you are using a shared computer.

**Order and contract**   
We save the contract text and send you an email immediately after receiving your order with your order data. You can [view our terms and conditions here](http://www.juniqe.com/terms) at any time. If you are registered on our website, you can view past orders in your customer account. You can use various payment methods on our shop. Your credit card or account details are collected and processed directly by the respective payment service provider and are not saved by us. We have absolutely no access to your payment information. For specific information, refer to the respective privacy policy of your payment provider.

**Anti-spam policy**   
JUNIQE does not tolerate any spam. That does not mean, however, that we can prevent spam on the internet. If you think that you have received an unsolicited email from us, please contact [service@juniqe.com](mailto:service@juniqe.com) so that we can investigate the issue.

**Cookies  
**  
This website uses cookies. A cookie is a small text file with an identification number which, when using our website, is transferred and recorded on your computer, together with the other, requested data. Storing these cookies helps us to tailor our website accordingly to you and makes it easier to use, for example by saving certain information you enter so that you don’t have to constantly re-type it. The file is kept ready for later access and serves to authenticate the user. 

As cookies are just simple files and not executable programs, they pose no danger to your computer. Depending on the chosen preferences in your internet browser, it may automatically accept cookies. This preference can be changed, and the storage of cookies completely disabled or deactivated in such a way that the user is notified as soon as a cookie is saved. In the case of a complete disabling of cookies, however, certain functions of the website will no longer be available or only in a limited form.

**1\. Session cookies**  
Session cookies are deleted once you close your browser.

**2\. Permanent cookies**   
We also use cookies that remain on your hard drive. Their expiration date is set to a date in the future. When visiting our website again, permanent cookies automatically recognise that you were already here and which options and settings you prefer, along with any text you may have entered into fields on our forms.

**3\. Use of third-party cookies**   
We work with several advertising partners who help us make our internet service and the JUNIQE website more interesting for you. Therefore, we also store cookies from partner organisations on your hard drive. These are temporary cookies that delete themselves automatically after a given period of time. Cookies from partner organisations are mostly deleted after a few days or within 24 months, and, in individual cases, after several years. The cookies from our partner organisations do not contain any personally-identifying data. Data is only collected under a user ID which at no point will be combined with personally-identifying data about you. You can object to data collection and storage for the purposes of web analysis at any time with future effect by letting us know with an email to [service@juniqe.com](mailto:service@juniqe.com)

**Google Analytics with the extension “anonymize IP”**

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. ("Google"). Google Analytics uses “cookies”. The information on your use of this website generated by the cookie (including your IP address) will be transferred to and stored on a Google server in the USA. Google adheres to the “EU-US privacy shield” framework for transatlantic exchanges of personal data. Google will use this information for the purpose of evaluating your use of the website, compiling reports about website activities for us, and to provide other services related to website and internet use. 

Google may also transfer this information to third parties as required by law or if said third parties process this data on behalf of Google. In any event, Google will not associate your IP address with other data held by Google. You can prevent these cookies being stored by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser; however, we wish to point out that doing so may mean you will not be able to enjoy the full functionality of this website. 

If you do not wish information about your website usage to be passed to Google Analytics, you can prevent this by installing a deactivation add-on for your browser. The current link for this plugin is: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>. 

In addition, JUNIQE uses the following Google Analytics advertising functions: Adwords, retargeting, reports on impressions on the Google Display Network, and reports on performance according to demographic characteristics and interests. 

If you wish to deactivate Google Analytics’ advertising functions, follow this link for Google’s privacy policy on advertising: https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads. Alternatively, you can also visit the deactivation page on the Network Advertising Initiative’s (NAI) website and follow their instructions and explanations: <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>

**Use of Facebook plugins**

Our website uses social plugins (“plugins”) provided by the social network Facebook. These services are provided by Facebook Inc. 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, California, 94025, USA (“Facebook”). You can find an overview of these plugins and their appearance here: 

When you visit one of our pages, these plugins establish a direct connection between your browser and Facebook’s servers. The contents of the plugin are communicated directly to your browser and integrated into the webpage. By integrating plugins, Facebook receives the information that your browser has visited the respective page of our website, even if you do not have a profile on the social network or are not currently logged in. This information (including your IP address) is transferred directly to Facebook’s servers and stored there. 

If you are logged into Facebook, the platform can match your visit to our website with your Facebook profile. When you interact with plugins, for example by clicking on the “like” button, the corresponding information will also be transmitted to Facebook’s servers and stored there. In addition, this information will be published on the social network and shown to your contacts there. For the purpose and scope of this data collection, information on further processing and usage of data by Facebook, and your legal rights and privacy settings relating to this, please refer to Facebook’s privacy policy: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/update>

If you do not wish for Facebook to match data collected through visiting our website to your Facebook profile, you must log out of the network before visiting our website. You can also completely prevent these plugins from loading with add-ons for your browser, for example with the script blocker “NoScript” (<http://noscript.net/>).

**Re-targeting  
**   
Our website uses a so-called re-targeting technology to make your online experience more interesting. This makes it possible to reach internet users who are already interested in our shop and products on other websites through adverts. We believe that personalised, interest-related ads are generally more interesting for internet users. The insertion of these ads on the websites of our partners works through cookies and by analysing previous user behaviour. This form of advertising is completely anonymous. No personalised data will be saved, and a user profile will not be merged with your personalised data.

**Criteo**

This website uses the Criteo service of Criteo SA, Rue Blanche, 75009 Paris, France (<http://www.criteo.com/>). Via this service, users who have already visited our website once and have shown interest in our offers are shown specific advertisements on this website and on internet pages which also use the Criteo service. The insertion of these ads is based on information about your visits to these respective internet pages, which are, among other things, saved in cookies on your computer. These text files are read within the context of subsequent website visits for specific product recommendations.

For this purpose, a randomly generated identification number is saved in your cookies. Neither this number nor information about your visits to these sites can be attributed to you personally. Under no circumstances will this data be used to personally identify you as the visitor of our website. You can prevent this information from being saved and used by the Criteo service by clicking the following link (<https://www.criteo.com/privacy/>) and by setting the “Opt-Out” button to “on”. By selecting “on”, a new opt-out cookie will be stored in your browser. This cookie tells Criteo’s service to no longer collect and process data about your user behaviour. You can reactivate this function by setting the opt-out button to “off” again. Please note that this setting must be adjusted for each browser you use. Alternatively, you can select the option "opt-out of all linked browsers" directly below Criteo's opt-out button. If all the cookies in your browser are deleted, the opt-out cookie will be deleted as well.

**Snowplow Analytics**

We use a web-tracking solution by Snowplow Analytics Limited, 32-38 Scrutton Street, London, UK (“Snowplow”). We use data collected by Snowplow exclusively for statistical purposes. In addition to this, we store a cookie in your browser in order to recognise returning users as such. The Snowplow cookie contains a date and a non-traceable, random combination number (“hash”), as well as the number of the current session. 

Each time a page is requested, the following data is transmitted to and stored by Snowplow: 

\- Current timestamp   
\- URL of the target website (“target URL”) and the URL of the website you are coming from (“referrer URL”)   
\- Contents of the cookies   
\- IP address, which is anonymised before reaching the Snowplow server, and your browser port   
\- Name, version, and language of your browser and operating system as transmitted by the browser of the website visitor, i.e. you 

Further information relating to this can be found in Snowplow’s privacy policy: <https://snowplowanalytics.com/privacy-policy/>

**Dynamic Yield**

This website uses Dynamic Yield, a recommendation tool by Dynamic Yield Ltd., Highlands House, Basingstoke Road, Spencers Wood, Reading, Berkshire, England RG7 1NT (Dynamic Yield). Our online service is optimised by the recommendation tool Dynamic Yield to make your visit to our website a personalised experience through tailored recommendations and content. In doing this, we use the content of your previously visited sites to recommend you comparable or thematically-related products or other content you might find relevant. 

Dynamic Yield collects pseudonymised information about your user activity on our website. In the process, cookies are used, through which only pseudonymised information is saved under a randomly generated ID (pseudonym). Your IP addresses are only saved anonymously. You are not personally identifiable, nor can you be at a later date. You can disable data collection by Dynamic Yield by clicking on the following link. If you do this, an opt-out cookie will be created which prevents future collection of data relating to your visits to our website: <https://www.dynamicyield.com/platform-privacy-policy/>

You can find more information on the tracking technologies we use at the following link: [https://www.dynamicyield.com](https://www.dynamicyield.com/)

**contentsquare**  

On our website, contentsquare S.A.S. technologies use cookies to collect pseudonymised information about the website visitors' interactions for the purposes of marketing as well as the optimisation of user-friendliness of our website.

The information generated by the cookie relating to your website usage is generally transferred to a contentsquare server and stored there. The IP address transmitted by your browser is not brought into association with any other contentsquare data. contentsquare guarantees that your IP address will be shortened so that all data can be collected anonymously.

The following cookies are stored by contentsquare:

  * _cs_id, to recognise users who return to the website (up to 13 months)
  * _cs_s, a session cookie which is created at the beginning of the website visit and deleted 30 minutes after the last page view

Possibility of opting-out of the process:

You can prevent these cookies being stored by selecting the appropriate settings in your browser; however, we wish to point out that in doing so you might not be able to enjoy the full functionality of our services.

To prevent data capture by contentsquare, you can click on the following link: <http://optout.contentsquare.net/>. Thus, an opt-out cookie is implemented which prevents your data being stored when you visit our website in the future. The opt-out cookie only functions in this browser and for this website and is stored on your device. If you delete the cookies from your browser, you will need to reset the opt-out cookie. In order to prevent contentsquare storing data across multiple devices, you must carry out the outlined opt-out procedure on every system you use.

**Integration of the Trusted Shops Trustbadge**

We have integrated the Trusted Shops Trustbadge on this website in order to display our Trusted Shops Trustmark and offer Trusted Shops products to customers after placing an order. 

This serves the protection of our legitimate interests in the optimal marketing of our offer according to art. 6 (1) 1 lit f GDPR that are overriding in the process of balancing of interests. The Trustbadge and the advertised trust badge services are offered by Trusted Shops GmbH, Subbelrather Str. 15C, 50823 Cologne, Germany. 

With every use of the Trustbadge, the web server automatically saves a so-called server log file which contains e.g. your IP address, the date and time of the request, the volume of data transferred and the requesting provider (access data), and documents the request. Those access data are not analysed and are automatically overwritten no later than seven days after the end of your website visit. 

Other personal data are transferred to Trusted Shops only if you decide to use or have already registered to use Trusted Shops products after placing an order. In such a case, the contract concluded between you and Trusted Shops applies.

**Voucher offers from Sovendus GmbH**

In order to select a voucher offer you will currently find interesting, we will forward the pseudonymised hash value of your email address and your IP address in an encrypted form to Sovendus GmbH, Moltkestrasse 11, D-76133 Karlsruhe, Germany (“Sovendus”) (Art. 6 par. 1 f GDPR). The pseudonymised hash value of your email address is used to check if we have a record of any possibly existing objections to receive offers from Sovendus (Art. 21 par.3, Art. 6 par. 1 c GDPR). Your IP address will solely be used for data security purposes and, will usually be anonymised after seven days (Art. 6 Abs.1 f GDPR). Furthermore, we will forward your order number, order value with currency, session ID, coupon code, and time stamp in pseudonymised form to Sovendus for billing purposes (Art. 6 Abs.1 f GDPR). If you are interested in a voucher offer from Sovendus, there is no existing objection to receive such offers, and you click on the voucher banner only shown in this circumstance, we will forward your title, name and email address in encrypted form to Sovendus in order to prepare your voucher (Art. 6 par. 1 b, f GDPR). You can find further information about the processing of your data by Sovendus in their privacy policy: <https://www.sovendus.co.uk/privacy_policy>.

**Nosto**

This website uses Nosto, a web analysis service from Nosto Solutions GmbH, Schützenstr. 6, 10117 Berlin and Nosto Solutions Ltd., Bulevardi 21, 00180 Helsinki, Finland (“Nosto”). Nosto’s services make it possible to target visitors of our online shop who have already shown interest in our shop and products with personalised, interest-related adverts. Nosto collects and analyses the behaviour of customers on online shops and thus makes it possible to automatically calculate and display different types of intelligent product recommendations and other adverts. Nosto uses cookies. As a rule, information produced through these cookies on your use of this website is transferred to one of Nosto’s servers in the European Union and stored there. If IP-anonymisation is activated on this website, however, your IP address will be shortened by Nosto prior to this. Only in rare cases will your full IP address be transferred to Nosto’s servers and shortened there. Nosto uses this information on behalf of our website to evaluate your use of this website, show you personalised recommendations, compile reports on your website activities, and provide us with further services relating to your website and internet use.

**Privacy policy last updated:**   
March 27, 2019

We reserve the right to change this privacy policy with future effect at any time.
